<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tableau | Christopher Teixeira</title>
    <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/category/tableau/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://christopherteixeira.com/category/tableau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tableau</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Christopher Teixeira</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 21:03:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://christopherteixeira.com/images/icon_hu910a7331dda2ff3368fc6c9cea07b8f5_648158_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Tableau</title>
      <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/category/tableau/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Healthcare Coalition</title>
      <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/project/c19hcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 21:03:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://christopherteixeira.com/project/c19hcc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For several months, I had the opportunity to support decision makers in understanding the complexity around the evolving COVID-19 pandemic. Under this project, I had the ability to support two distinct efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vulnerable-population-dashboard&#34;&gt;Vulnerable Population Dashboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this effort, I was able to stand up a small team of data analysts, data scientists, and public health experts to take a quick look at how we might be able to define areas of the United States that were vulnerable to the virus. We pulled together several different data sources and used Tableau to allow people to explore the results. This dashboard was publicized by Tableau and is still available to review at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://c19hcc.org/resource/vulnerable-population&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://c19hcc.org/resource/vulnerable-population&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;analytics-working-group&#34;&gt;Analytics Working Group&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coalition grew over time to include many organizations, all of which were using data in different ways to support understanding the complexity of the pandemic or support decisions to return to office or normal operations. Each week, I coordinated a series of presentations, conversations, and projects between over 100 organizations. This allowed for a number of organizations to do some incredible analytics that you can find linked through the 
&lt;a href=&#34;www.c19hcc.org&#34;&gt;main website&lt;/a&gt;. Topics ranged from how to share and discover data between organizations, different approaches to answering a question, and novel ways to visualize and explain complex solutions to the average US citizen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis for specific Brand/Products</title>
      <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/project/sentiment-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://christopherteixeira.com/project/sentiment-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Analyze social media (Twitter) to determine sentiment around a client&amp;rsquo;s brand and specific products. Using R, analyzed tweets to determine shifts in sentiment over time about a client&amp;rsquo;s brand and general effectiveness of customer service. Produced visualizations through R and Tableau to help executives understand the sentiment analysis results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
