<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Christopher Teixeira</title>
    <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://christopherteixeira.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Christopher Teixeira</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://christopherteixeira.com/images/icon_hu910a7331dda2ff3368fc6c9cea07b8f5_648158_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up an Email Signature</title>
      <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/signature/setting-up-an-email-signature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/signature/setting-up-an-email-signature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email signatures are a great way to personalize your own responses. Many people out there by default say something like &amp;ldquo;Best, John&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Regards, Jane&amp;rdquo; which is very respectful, but also plain. If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to make a good first impression with a company or trying to win a contract, a formatted email signature can go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;simple-options&#34;&gt;Simple Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone you send an email to will have the ability to render a nicely formatted email signature using HTML, either for security reasons or perhaps due to bandwidth issues. That being said, you can easily organize the content in an email signature in a way that allows someone to read it quickly. First up, determine what you want for content in your signature. These days, we can have mutliple sites or links associated with our lives from social media (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn), professional facing sites (e.g., GitHub, Kaggle), or other miscellaneous ones you might want to show off. I recommend being selective and choosing a set that you want someone on the other end that you want them to potentially see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For simplicity, let&amp;rsquo;s aim at LinkedIn, GitHub, and my website. This allows us to craft a simple looking email that will render in anyone&amp;rsquo;s inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Teixeira &lt;br&gt;
christopherteixeira.com &lt;br&gt;
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/christopherteixeira/ &lt;br&gt;
Twitter: twitter.com/ct_analytics &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple and readible, yet you can see that with all these links a little HTML will make it even easier for another person to follow you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;html-options&#34;&gt;HTML Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get in, its important to take note of what email provider and software you use. Not all of them will let you set up an email signature consisting of raw HTML code. Email clients like Gmail will let you format your text (i.e., bold, underline, add an image, etc.) but its not as flexible as you might like. If you&amp;rsquo;re limited by that, then you can just work with the example above to add some formatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I use Spark which gives me the full flexibility of setting up an HTML signature. It&amp;rsquo;s not too hard to craft something using tables and pictures, however, there are some great sites out there that will do the hard work for you. Here&amp;rsquo;s a couple sites to get started with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hubspot.com/email-signature-generator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HubSpot Email Signature Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://si.gnatu.re/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://si.gnatu.re/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://si.gnatu.re/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://si.gnatu.re/&lt;/a&gt; since it gave me a few more options I liked. However, it&amp;rsquo;s only available to edit for 30 days. If you want to edit it on day 31, you either edit the raw HTML yourself or start from scratch. I recommend pitching in the $5 since this site is incredible. I was able to generate the following signature which I&amp;rsquo;m currently using still:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table width=&#34;300&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;vertical-align:top;padding-right:10px&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img style=&#34;border:none;&#34;width=&#34;100&#34;src=&#34;https://s1g.s3.amazonaws.com/43c4c2f551be55f253472cb3def28ceb.jpeg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;border-left:solid #000000 2px;&#34; width=&#34;12&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;vertical-align: top;text-align:left;color:#212529;font-size:12px;font-family:tahoma;;text-align:left&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;
          &lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:5px;color:#212529;font-size:15px;font-family:tahoma&#34;&gt;Christopher Teixeira&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:5px;color:#212529;font-size:12px;font-family:tahoma&#34;&gt;Using Data for Social Good&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;padding-right:5px&#34;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ct_analytics&#34; style=&#34;display: inline-block;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;img width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34; src=&#34;https://s1g.s3.amazonaws.com/28597d480b109b5483f87cda4245435b.png&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter&#34; style=&#34;border:none;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;padding-right:5px&#34;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&#34;https://linkedin.com/in/christopherteixeira&#34; style=&#34;display: inline-block;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;img width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34; src=&#34;https://s1g.s3.amazonaws.com/affc8f54dec2b8991dc1e982f054d968.png&#34; alt=&#34;LinkedIn (Personal)&#34; style=&#34;border:none;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;padding-right:5px&#34;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ct-analytics&#34; style=&#34;display: inline-block;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;img width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34; src=&#34;https://s1g.s3.amazonaws.com/cedb8206a2a61cb5489bb6976efedf14.png&#34; alt=&#34;Github&#34; style=&#34;border:none;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.christopherteixeira.com&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:none;color:#0088CC;&#34;&gt;www.christopherteixeira.com&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up an email using AWS</title>
      <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/setting-up-an-email-using-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/setting-up-an-email-using-aws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t followed my other posts, this website was created using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt; in R. While building this site though, I decided to go off track in the tutorial to host it via Amazon Web Services (AWS) via their S3 buckets. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty straight forward process with a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/WebsiteHosting.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;detailed tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on hosting a static website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was less straight forward was setting up an email address to use with this website. This post will outline the major steps I took and aim at providing others with tips to follow for creating a professional email address to go with your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-the-email-address&#34;&gt;Getting the email address&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you followed the tutorial for setting up a static website, then you not only have a public S3 bucket, but also a domain registered using Route 53 or a similar service. The next step is to explore AWS Simple Email Service or SES. Like other AWS services, you can do this via the AWS CLI tools or their browser. I used their browser interface for this but replicated the steps using CLI just to see if it felt any easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you follow the AWS tutorials like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/getting-started/hands-on/send-an-email/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;, it sounds incredibly simple: just create one, verify it, and open your email client to receive it. However, in order to verify your email you first need to have the ability to receive and store emails that by default won&amp;rsquo;t be available with a custom email. I did this inside another S3 bucket but you can do this in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you actually create the email, you need a rule set for receiving the email. This 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/ses/latest/DeveloperGuide/receiving-email-receipt-rules.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; details gives you the steps and tips to consider. For me, it was simple enough to just list the domain as a recipient and determine the specific email later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to verify the email. This requires setting up the email, clicking verify, going to the folder you identified in the corresponding S3 bucket, and making sure a file appeared there. If it did, then you can open and copy+paste the link into your browser to finish verifying the email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-your-email-address&#34;&gt;Using your email address&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, this email address you just created is in the AWS SES sandbox. You can email anyone you have verified in here but for most practical purposes this won&amp;rsquo;t be sufficient. I want to be able to email anyone from this address using something like Spark. The next step is then to file a support ticket to do this. This 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/ses/latest/DeveloperGuide/request-production-access.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; gives you the details and I found it incredibly quick (about 10 hours) for them to review and approve this transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next step is to set up credentials for an SMTP server so you can retrieve and send emails using something other than AWS. This 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/ses/latest/DeveloperGuide/smtp-credentials.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; outlines the steps for getting your credentials. This is a key step, do not lose those credentials!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various email clients and services might have slightly different steps, but I like using Spark for managing my many inboxes. They give you several options, from setting up a new 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sparkmailapp.com/help/141-add-more-email-accounts-to-spark.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;inbox&lt;/a&gt; to setting up an 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sparkmailapp.com/help/154-set-up-an-email-alias.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;alias&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once that&amp;rsquo;s completed, you should be good to start sending emails! However, receiving emails is a slightly different story. Having the SMTP is only part of the answer as you&amp;rsquo;ll see. Receiving emails from unverified email addresses requires an extra step that requires setting up a function to forward incoming emails to the email associated with your alias. Luckily, this website outlines it all for you so head over to the traveling squid and read his posts 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://thetravellingsquid.com/2019/05/27/send-emails-with-gmail-using-amazon-simple-email-service/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://thetravellingsquid.com/2019/05/30/domain-specific-email-on-gmail-with-amazon-ses/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next post will be around setting up a professional looking signature for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similar Players in MLB: Comparison against Baseball-Reference</title>
      <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/mlb_player_similarity/20191113_mlb_player_similarity_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/mlb_player_similarity/20191113_mlb_player_similarity_3/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;As many of you are aware, Baseball-Reference calculates a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baseball-reference.com/about/similarity.shtml&#34;&gt;similarity score&lt;/a&gt; for each player against other players. Although this is an accepted way to calculate the similarity between two players, I wanted to see if my methodology compares. I ran my methodology for Hank Aaron (someone we all know and can understand the comparisons) and compared the list I got against the list Baseball-Reference posted. First, let’s look at what Baseball-Reference has:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willie Mays (782)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barry Bonds (748)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frank Robinson (667)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stan Musial (666)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Babe Ruth (645)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ken Griffey (629)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carl Yastrzemski (627)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rafael Palmeiro (611)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alex Rodriguez (610)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mel Ott (602)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think anyone would argue with any of these players. However, what’s the list of players I came up with? Well, here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willie Mays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frank Robinson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al Kaline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ernie Banks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billy Williams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brooks Robinson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roberto Clemente&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ken Boyer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norm Cash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carl Yastrzemski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s interesting about my list is there are certainly players that don’t seem comparable to Hank Aaron. The question then becomes, how did they make it here? Quickly looking at the numbers you can see that I included more statistics for comparison than Baseball-Reference. In addition, I used a weighting scheme for comparing various statistics. Here’s the full list of comparisons. Note that the lower the number, the closer they are in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[insert table]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So which one is right? I think its easy to say that Baseball-Reference seems more accurate, but I am continuously looking to improve this methodology and see how that impacts the results. Keep tuned for the final version of the code and methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similar Players in MLB: Calculating Similarity</title>
      <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/mlb_player_similarity/20191110_mlb_player_similarity_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/mlb_player_similarity/20191110_mlb_player_similarity_2/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in Similar Players in MLB, I want to be able to see how similar players can be. I decided to take a somewhat different approach by looking at how a player’s career compares against another player’s career. In order to put things in terms of a career, I didn’t want to simply sum up their statistics or normalize given the number of years they played. I wanted to be able to compare a player’s second year against another player’s second year. This isn’t a simple problem though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First part of the problem, what statistics do you use to compare two different players? Using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seanlahman.com/baseball-archive/statistics/&#34;&gt;Lahman Database&lt;/a&gt;, I had easy access to the common statistics like games played, at bats, runs scored, hits, doubles, triples, etc. However, this database doesn’t simply just have the counting stats by year. It is a compiled record of stats by league and team. In order to simplify the data collection, I aggregated the information up to the combination of player and year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second part of the problem, how accurate is it to compare a player’s first year against another player’s first year? Is it possible to correct for a player being sent to the majors a little early or taking a couple years to develop? This means being able to compare a player’s first year against another player’s first, second, or perhaps third year to determine the closest match. How do you adjust for a player’s third year against a player’s first year? While I use SAS at work, I don’t have access to it’s functions at home. I noticed that SAS’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.sas.com/documentation/cdl/en/etsug/60372/HTML/default/viewer.htm#similarity_toc.htm&#34;&gt;PROC SIMILARITY&lt;/a&gt; has the capability for being able to calculate the minimum distance between two time series. Consider the example below of two player’s games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://christopherteixeira.com/_post/20191110_mlb_player_similarity_2_files/figure-html/player_graph-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that they’re not the exact same, but you can see the similarity between the two. Using dynamic programming, you can find the minimum distance between these two time series. Distance between two time series can be a simple euclidean distance or something slightly different. However, I don’t have access to SAS at home. Luckily enough, I was able to find a package in R that has this capability. Using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/dtw/index.html&#34;&gt;“dtw” package&lt;/a&gt;, you can easily calculate the distance between two different time series. Applying this package to the above example, gives you the results below. This three-way plot shows each player’s data in the margins and how each point maps. The closer the plot is to Y=X implies the how close the mapping of one series of data is to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://christopherteixeira.com/_post/20191110_mlb_player_similarity_2_files/figure-html/comparison-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next problem is how to use all of this similarity to figure out what players are actually similar to each other. Keep an eye out for my next blog on using Social Network Analysis to cluster these players together and incorporating more than just Games Played.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similar Players in MLB</title>
      <link>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/mlb_player_similarity/20191108_mlb_player_similarity_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://christopherteixeira.com/post/mlb_player_similarity/20191108_mlb_player_similarity_1/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;It’s a common question to compare baseball players against each other. The question is what do you actually compare? Their playing styles? Positions they played? Teams they played for? Eras they played in? There are several dimensions to which this problem’s complexity increases dramatically. In fact, several people now try to compare &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baseball-reference.com/players/p/puigya01.shtml&#34;&gt;Yasiel Puig&lt;/a&gt; against &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baseball-reference.com/players/t/troutmi01.shtml&#34;&gt;Mike Trout&lt;/a&gt; (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.espn.com/blog/los-angeles/dodger-report/post/_/id/5458/what-to-expect-and-not-to-expect-from-yasiel-puig&#34;&gt;Mark Saxon&lt;/a&gt;). However, how would you compare them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m interested in developing an analytical technique that will remove the manual labor of looking at statistics. By removing that tedious task, it would be interesting to see how player’s careers compare against other player careers. I’m hoping that in the end, I can use this as a significant factor in being able to predict whether a player will end up in the Hall of Fame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to come on this topic, but here’s a little tease:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data sourced from Sean Lahman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Techniques include:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Network Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logistic Regression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programmed entirely in R and RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next problem is how to use all of this similarity to figure out what players are actually similar to each other. Keep an eye out for my next blog on using Social Network Analysis to cluster these players together and incorporating more than just Games Played.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
