<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAS | Christopher Teixeira</title>
    <link>/category/sas/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/sas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>SAS</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Christopher Teixeira</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu720a42e4c39acd29e79ebd4769940488_141053_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>SAS</title>
      <link>/category/sas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>JIEDDO - Operations Research and Systems Analysis Support</title>
      <link>/project/jieddo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/jieddo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I support JIEDDO using various analytical techniques including Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP) and Regression Analysis. I created and tested a metric to help support decision making for various groups of people working with JIEDDO. I transferred complicated projects in EXCEL and ACCESS to SAS, improving the run-time and product quality. I created SAS Stored Processes to help streamline report generation, support business intelligence, and produce high quality graphics for all customers. I wrote a process to clean raw data and format the data using regular expression parsing on ingest of the data feeds. I integrated a process to parse XML files and create new databases from the results, making new sources of data available for a multitude of colleagues. I designed a database to enhance reporting and help determine an optimal solution to a resource allocation problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: US soldiers examine evidence at an IED training site at the National Training Center at Fort Irwin, California, US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Claims Fraud</title>
      <link>/project/aetna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/aetna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worked with a team to determine the best use of IBM’s analytical skills to help Aetna improve their business. Modified a SAS multiplicative regression model to be more flexible with data and improve efficiency. Determine the important factors in improving care management efficiency for existing programs at Aetna.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Analysis of Defensive Production in Major League Baseball</title>
      <link>/project/mqp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/mqp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While many statistical measures have been devised to measure team and player performance in professional baseball, relatively little work has been done to study and improve measures of defensive performance. This project’s goals were to model defensive contribution to team performance and develop related measures of individual player defensive production. Factor analysis was employed to extract positional factors and combine them with pitching and offensive measures into a final logistic regression model to determine effects of defense on team performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
