<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL | Christopher Teixeira</title>
    <link>/category/sql/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>SQL</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Christopher Teixeira</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu720a42e4c39acd29e79ebd4769940488_141053_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>SQL</title>
      <link>/category/sql/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>JIEDDO - Operations Research and Systems Analysis Support</title>
      <link>/project/jieddo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/jieddo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I support JIEDDO using various analytical techniques including Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP) and Regression Analysis. I created and tested a metric to help support decision making for various groups of people working with JIEDDO. I transferred complicated projects in EXCEL and ACCESS to SAS, improving the run-time and product quality. I created SAS Stored Processes to help streamline report generation, support business intelligence, and produce high quality graphics for all customers. I wrote a process to clean raw data and format the data using regular expression parsing on ingest of the data feeds. I integrated a process to parse XML files and create new databases from the results, making new sources of data available for a multitude of colleagues. I designed a database to enhance reporting and help determine an optimal solution to a resource allocation problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: US soldiers examine evidence at an IED training site at the National Training Center at Fort Irwin, California, US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
